Ranjit Ghadge

Data Science Trainee

A dedicated and motivated Data Science enthusiast with a strong interest in Python, Statistics, and SQL, possessing practical experience in Data Analytics, Data Visualization, and Machine Learning. Along with technical proficiencies, effective communication, and teamwork collaboration are prioritized.

ranjitghadge555@gmail.com

09130577082

linkedin.com/in/ranjit-ghadge

ш,

github.com/Ranjitghadge





ACADEMIC PROJECTS

11/2022 - 12/2022

Tags: Unsupervised ML, Clustering, Count Vectorizer, NLP, Nltk, K-Means, clustering

- Developing a Recommender System which Recommends Netflix movies and TV shows based on a user's favorite movie or TV show which uses NLP model and a K- Means Clustering model to make these recommendations.
- Employed NLP techniques such as text cleaning, removing stopwords & punctuations, stemming, lemmatization & TFIDF vectorizer.
- Experimented with K-means clustering and evaluated them using Elbow method, Silhouette Analysis to determine the optimal number of clusters
- Got the optimal number of clusters equal to 25 and from this clustering analysis, created Netflix movies and tv shows recommendation system.

Credit Card Default Prediction

AlmaBetter Verified 🗷

10/2022 - 11/2022

Tags: Feature Engineering, Anomaly Detection, Hyperparameter Tuning, Decision Tree

- Developed a supervised ML model to predict whether the customer is likely to default on their credit card or not.
- Conducted a thorough EDA to handle missing values, label encoding, one hot encoding, and feature engineering & enhancing data comprehension.
- Handled Class imbalance using SMOTE technique. Split the dataset into train and test and carried out hyperparameter tuning using GridSearchCV.
- Experimented with algorithms such as Logistic Regression, Random Forest, XGBoost, Decision tree, and SVM and selected XGBoost based on a Test Accuracy of 87.10% and AUC score of 87.4%.

Bike Sharing Demand Prediction

AlmaBetter Verified 🗷

09/2022 - 10/2022

Tags: Data Wrangling, EDA, Linear Regression, Random Forest, Hyperparameter Tuning

- Provide the bike rental company of Seoul city with accurate demand of the rental bikes required, for each hour of the day.
- Employed feature engineering techniques and data preprocessing. Built a regression model using linear regression, L1 & L2 regression, and Random Forest Regressor to predict the bike demand in Seoul city.
- Achieved 91% adjusted R2 score with Random Forest Regressor and hyperparameter tuning using GridSearchCV.



Expertise in Language & Tools (x/5)

SQL-4.5 || Tableau-4.5 || Python-4 || Excel-4.5 || PowerBi-4.5 || Lookers Studio-4.5 || GitHub-4.5

Platform

Jupyter Notebook, MySQL, Google Colab, VS Code, PostgreSQL, Tableau, Power BI, Looker Studio

ML Framework

Sci-kit Learn, Pandas, NumPy, MatplotLib, Seaborn



WORK EXPERIENCE

QS & Billing EngineerErecon Spaces Pvt.Ltd

09/2021 - 03/2023

Pune.Maharashtra

Skills: Excel, Tableau, Data Visualization, Good Communication

- Implemented efficient invoicing systems, optimizing cash flow management, reducing payment cycle time, and resolving billing discrepancies with clients and vendors.
- Streamlined complex quantity surveying through cost optimization, rate analysis, accurate tendering processes
 efficient contract negotiation
- Proactively tracked project costs and billing cycles, conducting reconciliations of material consumption.



TRAINING EXPERIENCE

Data Science Trainee

Almabetter 🗷

06/2022 - Present

Bengaluru, Karnataka

Skills: Python, SQL, Machine Learning, Tableau, Power BI, Teamwork

- Learned skills like Feature Engineering, EDA, Tableau, PowerBI, and Looker Studio.
- Worked on Case studies Like Danny's Dinner and Pizza Runner and gained proficiency in SQL and Python.
- Got hands-on experience in SQL, Python & ML Algorithms of Supervised & Unsupervised ML.



ACHIEVEMENTS

Gold Badge in Python and SQL

Hackerrank || 650+ points in SQL and 405+ points in Python

LinkedIn Badge in SQL 🗷

In the top 15% of 2.0M people.



EDUCATION

B.E in Civil Engineering

DIET, Satara 🗷

Percentage - 70.11% || 2016- 2020



PUBLICATIONS

edium Bloa

Machine Learning Use Cases in Banking, Finance, and Insurance ♂

2023